Now, how to insert elements into to the array, we have this code here.
We start by declaring and creating an array.
Integer array and double array, because we have two angled brackets.
I name it as array to the equal new and having two rows and four columns.
OK, so the total number of elements is two times four is equal to eight.
Now I need to create an object of scanner, so object of scanner.
It helps you to get the input from the user.
So there is an iMessage message called Please enter the values to be added, and then we are getting
these values from the user input and stored them into to the array.
Since we are working with the array, we are working with a nested loop.
So a for loop, the first outer loop, which is indexed as I end iterated through integer I is iterating
through four zero till two through all the elements.
So zero one and.
Do but do is not included, so zero and one, so there are two rows and zero and one and the next and
the nested loop is four indexed as J.
So it's at the rate that the using an MJ that loops through all elements from zero till four four is
not included.
So we have zero one, two and three.
So we have four columns.
OK, so we are iterating using AI and rose and using J in columns.
OK.
And we start storing every element that the user import or added as input and store it in the exact
index.
So the first element the user entered it will be stored at row zero and and index of that column is
zero.
So at zero zero add zero column.
OK, this is the array 2D.
This is how we store the elements and systems that are that print Alan when it finishes the first row.
It will go to and print our next line.
Now let's go to our ADC and a Java ID.
And you can work with a C or Python, and we will see later on how to work with other ideas.
But till now, we are mainly we are working with Java because it is more and more like likely to be
used in courses, in university courses and interviews.
And the C is similar to Java, so Java and C are very similar to to each other.
So we are working with Java.
OK.
So I need to create this matrix, this array today, and I need to store at the first throw and the
first column number one and the last and the second row and the fourth column.
I store eight and I continue with the numbers as they.
So let's go to the idea and see how this works.
This is our idea.
It is called and the intelligent idea, and we are using it for Java compiling and Java code so you
can download it directly.
Download Intelligent Idea.
This is here.
OK.
It's the jet brains dot com idea download so you can download the Ultimate with a free 30 days trial
or their free built on open source, which is here and we are using that community for JVM and Android
development.
This is the difference between the two versions.
We use that community edition and it's very, very good idea to be putting all your codes and try to
work with your codes and compile your codes inside Java so you can download it from here.
It's very simple and direct link and go through the steps, and it's very simple.
OK, now back to the idea we have create the two, the array.
As I told you, it has two columns, two rows and four columns and we have got the input.
From the user using this kind of object that we have imported to package Java that you tell the scanner
and using a for loop, we are getting that user input now and storing it inside the editing.
Now look, guys.
This is the council telling us to please enter the values to be added.
We start by one enter two, three and four.
You see, guys, there is a space.
So this is their print alone here because the first loop has been finished.
Now I equal to zero till now.
When it finishes this loop, I becomes one.
Because it's printed and goes up, adding, I buy one.
And it becomes one.
And now it's waiting for that fifth, sixth, seventh and eighth.
That if I click enter it prints and new line and it stops the program because we are adding their numbers
to it, to the array that has two rows and four columns, and we have eight.
Elements, OK, so this is how we add elements into it to the array using.